Abdelhak RAHMOUNI

Full Stack Developer

+213 780 48 96 07 | rahmouni.abdelhak.1@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rahmouni-abdelhak | github.com/noisy96 | noisy96.github.io

SUMMARY

I'm a computer science master's degree graduate and an avid reader with insatiable curiosity. I have more than 3 years of experience building software for desktop, mobile and web. I am autonomous and a self-learner that loves to constantly push boundaries.

EDUCATION

University of Science and Technology of Oran - MB

Master degree in Information & Data Systems

University of Science and Technology of Oran - MB

Licence degree in Computer Science

Sept. 2019 - Sept. 2021

Oran, Algeria

Oran, Algeria Sept. 2016 - Juin 2019

EXPERIENCE

Fullstack developer (Freelance)

Aug 2021 – Sept 2021

Barsha Technology

Gabes, Tunisia

- Created an RGPD (Rglement Gnral sur les Donnes Personnelles) compliance checking tool for a client based offshore.
- Implemented introduction slideshow to showcase the procedure
- Slide animation for seamless progression through compliance checking steps.
- Calculate compliance score and display it at the end.
- Implement Google Sheets API as backend to save data to.

President

Sept 2017 - Aug 2021

UDev Community

Oran, Algeria

- Second best speaker for delivering a talk at the community's annual conference about habit forming technology
- Prepared & delivered a workshop about LaTeX for 40 students approaching graduation
- Effectively reformed & polished the recruiting process by decreasing the human intervention needed
- Oversaw the strategies & policies surrounding the community's engagement with the public
- Participated in entrepreneurial and competitive programming programs

Store Manager

Juin 2013 - 2018

Syrine Habillement

Oran, Algeria

- The job consisted of managing a medium size clothing store with 5 employees, the main tasks varied according to needs
- Answering customer needs & inquiries
- · Initiating offers and following through until the closing of the purchase
- Keeping track of the inventory and releasing needed items report at the end of the day

PROJECTS

Inception Extension | Chrome API, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Sept 2020

- Developed a browser extension that allows a user to travel to the very first commit of any Github repository
- Used vanillaJS DOM manipulation to place a button on the page seamlessly
- Fetched Github API for the proper commit hash for constructing the url

Reading Meter | React, Material Design, JavaScript, TravisCI

July 2020

- Developed a single purpose minimalist webapp that estimates the time needed to read a given text
- Implemented continuous delivery using TravisCI to build the app upon a new release

• Deployed the webapp on Github Pages

Bindex | Flutter, Dart, Firebase, Material Design

Juin 2019

- · Developed a social media mobile app for buying, borrowing and exchanging books for local readers
- · Integrated Google Maps API for position based browsing
- · Integrated Google Books API for retrieving data about the books being added

studentPortal | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL

Feb 2018

- · Built a dynamic, fully responsive web site for posting campus announcement as images from scratch
- Connect to a MySQL database & file I/O for handing uploads
- Built an admin panel secured by .htaccess

JavaMailServer | Java, SMTP, IMAP, Sockets

Feb 2020

- Implementation of an e-mail server that uses SMTP/IMAP protocols and allow registered users to send and receive emails.
- Designed the software architecture using the agents metaphor.
- Implemented connection between the client and server application using Java Sockets.

snailCompiler | Java, Compiler design

Dec 2019

- Implementation of a compiler for a hypothetical programming language called Snail.
- Implmented lexical, syntaxic and semantic analysers.
- · Gained valuable insights about the inner working of compilers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Java, JavaScript, C/C++, SQL, PL/SQL, HTML/CSS, Dart, PHP, Python

Frameworks: React, Express, Flutter

Developer Tools: Git, VS Code, Eclipse, TravisCI

Libraries: Bootstrap, JQuery, Java Swing

Design: Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Xd **Others**: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Wordpress, LaTeX

CERTIFICATIONS

- Responsive Web Design Certification FreeCodeCamp
- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification FreeCodeCamp
- Front End Libraries Certification FreeCodeCamp
- Ultra fast applications using Node.js Openclassroom
- Go Full-Stack With Node.js, Express, and MongoDB Openclassroom
- Manage Your Code Project With Git & Github Openclassroom